# **ALEXEY SHTANKO**

# Android Developer | iOS Developer

Phone: +380688005548 Skype: shtankoksu Github: Alexey Shtanko

Email: <a href="mailto:shtankopro@gmail.com">shtankopro@gmail.com</a>

Linkedin: <u>adamluissean</u>

## **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

More than 4 years of professional experience in mobile development for Android and iOS platforms. Strong knowledge of Kotlin and Java. Building native libraries for mobile clients, Android NDK expertise. Following Agile (Scrum) methodology principles. App Store and Google Play Market app delivering experience.

## **EDUCATION**

BS, Kherson State University, Software Engineering

2011 - 2015

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Multimedia NordicMiddle + Android Developer(Kotlin)December 2018 - Present2k-groupMiddle Android DeveloperJul 2017 - December 2018Wezom MobileJunior IOS DeveloperApr 2016 - Jul 2017Bonsite LLCJunior Android DeveloperMay 2014 - Jul 2015

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Kotlin, Java,, Swift

**Databases:** Sqlite(Android), Room(Android), Realm(Android/iOS)

Technical Tools: IntelliJ Idea, Android Studio, Xcode

**Technologies & Frameworks:** 

• OOP, MVVM, MVP, Design Patterns

 Android SDK, Retrofit, Picasso, OkHttp, Realm, GSON, Google Play Services, Clean Architecture, JUnit

Version Control Systems: Git

Build Tools: Maven, Gradle, Cocoa Pods, Fastlane

Development Environment & Bug Tracking Systems: Asana, Jira, Trello



## RECENTLY COMPLETED PROJECTS

#### **Brew Book**

Customer: Undisclosed private customer

Description: Brew Book is an application for pair with brew machine(IoT), starting and control

brewing process through Bluetooth or WiFi connection. Also the application includes brew recipes database, user can choose a recipe, get a lot of information

about recipe, or create own.

Position: Middle + Android developer

Technologies: Kotlin, Android, BLE, Websockets, RxJava, qr code recognition, Room, MVVM,

architecture components

Roles:

• Development from scratch

Links: <u>Brew Book</u>

## Fersk Fangst

Customer: Undisclosed private customer

Description: Fersk Fangst is a market for buying and selling food and great service. The market

is free to use, and collects farmers, hunters and fishermen in the same place to sell their unique foods. You are also invited to contribute if you have food or

experiences you want to sell to others.

Position: Middle Android developer

Technologies: Kotlin, Android, Retrofit, RxJava 2, Websockets

Roles:

• Development from scratch

Links: Fersk Fangst on Google Play

## **Social Network VPN Android Application**

Customer: Undisclosed private customer

Description: Yet another simple VPN client for Android. With an active service subscription,

user can create an encrypted and secure channel between devices and one of our

servers in over ten countries using VPN technology.

Position: Middle Android developer

Technologies: Java, Android, Kotlin, Retrofit, RxJava, Android NDK.

Roles:

• New features implementation

• Custom UI creation

Legacy code support

Links: Social Network VPN on Google Play

## **VPN Shield Android Application**

Customer: Undisclosed private customer

Description: A VPN client for Android. With an active service subscription, user can create an

encrypted and secure channel between devices and one of our servers in over ten

countries using VPN technology.

Position: Middle Android developer

Technologies: Java, Android, Kotlin, Retrofit, RxJava, Android NDK, Unit Testing, UI Testing.

Roles:

• New features implementation

Legacy code support

Links: <u>VPN Shield on Google Play</u>

## **Servolab Pro For Doctor Android Application**

Customer: Undisclosed private customer

Description: Android client for doctors. The application helps doctors referring customers for

consultation, review, or further action. Doctor can view list of laboratories and find it on the map. Doctor have an opportunity to view description specific laboratory details(location, work time, website, phone number, route). Doctor have access to a large list of professional services for laboratories and clinics, detailed descriptions of analyzes, details and peculiarities of their conduct and patient training. The patient receives a referral from the doctor and independently chooses the labs in the application. The doctor sees when the analysis is done and remotely

receives the research results without visiting the client.

Position: Middle Android developer

Technologies: Android, Java, Kotlin, Firebase, Retrofit, RxJava, REST Api, Google Play

Services, Google Gson, Dagger, Clean Architecture, MVP, Unit Testing, UI

Testing.

Roles:

• Maps module development

• Custom UI creation

• Architecture design and development

• New features implementation

Links: Servolab Pro on Google Play

#### **ULC Social Streaming iOS Application**

Customer: Undisclosed private customer

Description: A social network of live video broadcasts and games. User can play in simple

video games like rock-paper-scissors and streaming simultaneously. Also users can start two, three or four video sessions for talks with friends. Users can watch other live game or talk sessions. Application support game chat and simple friends

chat.

Position: Junior iOS developer

Technologies: Swift, Realm, Open GLES, iOS Media API, Websockets.

Roles:

Auth module developmentMedia module development

• Custom UI creation

• Video streaming module development

• Unity 3d game development and porting for iOS and Android

Links: <u>ULC on App Store</u> I <u>Google Play</u>

# **ТРЦ Fabrika Android Application**

Customer: Fabrika Shopping Mall Ukraine

Description: The application helps people to get information about different shops and view

discounts, view interesting events and view photos and videos from these events.

Position: Junior Android developer

Technologies: Java, Android, Realm, Retrofit, RxJava.

Roles:

• Full stack development

Links: Available locally